## **Ekaterina Ivankova**

Data Analyst (Junior/Intern)

## Profile

I have an analytical mind, sharp attention to details, rigorous need in keeping data structured and organised, experience in Web and Game development. Combining it with my genuine passion to video games, I have decided to find myself in that industry as a Data Analyst.

## Education

# Engineer's degree, Irkutsk National Research Technical University, Irkutsk, Russia

September 2009 — July 2014

Automated System of Data Processing and Management

## Data Analysis, Practicum by Yandex

March 2022 — December 2022

#### Selected projects:

- Diploma project 1 Analysed players in-game behaviour and engagement in the game "Space Brothers" and the correlation between their behaviour and the traffic sources in order to plan and optimise an advertising campaign.
- 2. Diploma project 2 Analysed an A/B test of a recommender system for the online store.
- 3. Analysed business metrics and estimated LTV and ROI of a marketing campaign.
- 4. Determined variables in order to define the market price of real estate items in order to build an automated system for tracking anomalies and fraudulent activities.

## **Data-Driven Product Management, GoPractice**

January 2023 — Present

- Understanding metrics, cohort analysis, marketing analytics.
- Analysing change with data and A/B tests, design of experiments.
- Unit economics, ROI, evaluation of marketing channels, types of growth channels, ASO.

## Math for Data analysts, Practicum by Yandex

February 2023 — Present

- Linear algebra
- Calculus
- Linear algebra in data analysis
- Probability theory and statistics

#### **Details**

London United Kingdom +447368356131 rikka.irk@gmail.com

#### Links

Github

#### **Skills**

Data Visualisation

Data Analysis

SQL

Python

Spreadsheets

Communication

## Languages

Russian

**English** 

Spanish

#### **Hobbies**

Traveling (visited 20 countries)
Hiking and backpacking
Photography
Painting and nail art
Film background acting

## Employment History

## QA Engineer at Sperasoft, Saint Petersburg, Russia

June 2015 — April 2017

- Worked in Sony PlayStation outsource team responsible for quality control of the PlayStation firmware and cross-platform Store.
- Led regular QA Regressions and assisted the QA Lead.
- Created an automated QA Regression KPI spreadsheet that reduced the amount of person-hours spent on the monthly reports.
- Organised regular inter-company QA knowledge sessions and two public QA meetups.

#### QA Engineer at Arcadia Inc., Saint Petersburg, Russia

May 2017 — April 2019

- Worked on several Web Service projects in a full-stack development teams.
- Participated in the System integration testing.
- Wrote copious amount of the SQL scripts for tests.
- Wrote basic automated tests in C#.

## Self-employment and art-projects, London, United Kingdom

May 2019 — September 2021

- After the relocation to London decided to try myself in art and blogging.
- I love painting and nail art so I spent sometime on developing my skills in art and photography.
- I created a blog for this hobby and made an attempt to monetise it.
- In the end I realised that I want to keep it as a hobby and not to turn it into a full-time job.